Where do you come from?
你来自哪里?
I come from England.
我来自英格兰.
What's the climate like in your country?
你们国家的气候怎么样?
It's mild, but it's not always pleasant.
气候温和, 但也不总是宜人的.
The weather's often cold in the North and windy in the East.
北部的天气常常寒冷, 东部则常常刮风.
It's often wet in the West and sometimes warm in the south.
西部常下雨, 南部有时则很暖和.
Which seasons do you like best?
你最喜欢哪些季节?
I like spring and summer.
我最喜欢春季和夏季.
The days are long and the nights are short.
此时白天长而夜晚短.
The sun rises early and sets late.
太阳升得早而落得晚.
I don't like autumn and winter.
我不喜欢秋季和冬季.
The days are short and the nights are long.
此时白天短而夜晚长.
The sun rises late and sets early.
太阳升得迟而落得早.
Our climate is not very good,
我们国家的气候并不很好,
but it's certainly interesting.
但又确实很有意思.
It's our favourite subject of conversation.
天气是我们最喜欢谈论的话题.